Office of the Dean of Arts, Sciences, and Engineering Records UA045
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Subject Files, 1946 -- 2006; 1980 -- 1989; UA045.005; 5.8 Linear Feet
  - Historical Subject Files, 1976 -- 2006; UA045.005.004
    - Center for Public Service 85-86, 1985 -- 1986; UA045.005.025.00007 (Box 25)
    - Center for Public Service 84-85, 1984 -- 1985; UA045.005.025.00008 (Box 25)
    - Continuing Education, 1976 -- 1998; UA045.005.025.00009 (Box 25)
    - Culture Option, 2003 -- 2005; UA045.005.025.00010 (Box 25)
    - Curriculm and Learning Transformation Symposium Spring, 1995; UA045.005.025.00011 (Box 25)
    - Dean of the Colleges, 1989 -- 1998; UA045.005.025.00012 (Box 25)
    - Dean of Students 1990-, 1983 -- 2000; UA045.005.025.00013 (Box 25)
    - Disablities, 1978 -- 1991; UA045.005.025.00014 (Box 25)
    - Faculty Development Teaching and Research, 1999; UA045.005.025.00015 (Box 25)
    - Faculty Recognition, 1997 -- 2001; UA045.005.025.00016 (Box 25)
    - Faculty Retirement, 1983 -- 1994; UA045.005.025.00017 (Box 25)
    - Fraternities and Sororities, 1984 -- 2005; UA045.005.025.00018 (Box 25)
    - FTE Counts, 1989 -- 1991; UA045.005.025.00019 (Box 25)
    - Fund for Undergraduate Education, 1984 -- 1991; UA045.005.025.00020 (Box 25)
    - Grant-in-Aid, 2002; UA045.005.025.00021 (Box 25)
    - GIS, 2000 -- 2001; UA045.005.025.00022 (Box 25)
    - Hazardous Materials, 1997 -- 1999; UA045.005.025.00023 (Box 25)
    - Tufts Faculty Access to Harvard Library, 1993; UA045.005.025.00024 (Box 25)
    - Health Services, 1979 -- 1996; UA045.005.025.00025 (Box 25)
    - HEI-II 1998-1999 PT/NTT Committee, 1998 -- 2000; UA045.005.025.00026 (Box 25)
    - Higher Education Data Sharing (HEDS), 2003; UA045.005.025.00027 (Box 25)
    - Higher Education Initiative, 1997 -- 1998; UA045.005.025.00028 (Box 25)
    - Housing, 1986 -- 1997; UA045.005.026.00001 (Box 26)
    - Internships, 1976 -- 2004; UA045.005.026.00002 (Box 26)
    - Institutional Planning, 1993 -- 1999; UA045.005.026.00003 (Box 26)
    - Intellectual Life, 1992 -- 1993; UA045.005.026.00004 (Box 26)
    - Joint Appointments, 1983 -- 1990; UA045.005.026.00005 (Box 26)
    - K-12, 1996 -- 2001; UA045.005.026.00006 (Box 26)
    - LA &J Dean for Natural and Social Sciences, 1997; UA045.005.026.00007 (Box 26)
    - Language Lab, 1979 -- 1988; UA045.005.026.00008 (Box 26)
    - Leaves, 1990 -- 1998; UA045.005.026.00009 (Box 26)
    - LBGC, 1989 -- 2000; UA045.005.026.00010 (Box 26)
    - Library, 1981 -- 1999; UA045.005.026.00011 (Box 26)
    - "Light on the Hill" Award, 1995 -- 2004; UA045.005.026.00012 (Box 26)
    - Lilly Endownment, 1988 -- 2001; UA045.005.026.00013 (Box 26)
    - Malden-Tufts Literacy Project, 1999 -- 2000; UA045.005.026.00014 (Box 26)
    - Maternity Policy, 1979 -- 2001; UA045.005.026.00015 (Box 26)
    - May Base, 1998 -- 1999; UA045.005.026.00016 (Box 26)
    - Mission Statements, 1990 -- 1993; UA045.005.026.00017 (Box 26)
    - MPH Program, 1995 -- 2000; UA045.005.026.00018 (Box 26)
    - Modified Strategic Review, 1991 -- 1992; UA045.005.026.00019 (Box 26)
    - National Urban Fellows Program, 1991 -- 1995; UA045.005.026.00020 (Box 26)
    - NIH, 1996 -- 1997; UA045.005.026.00021 (Box 26)
    - Nutrition Course, 2004; UA045.005.026.00022 (Box 26)
    - Nutrition School, 1976 -- 2000; UA045.005.027.00001 (Box 27)
    - Organization Consulting Reports, 1997; UA045.005.027.00002 (Box 27)
    - Outside Activities, 1981 -- 1988; UA045.005.027.00003 (Box 27)
    - Overseers [Folder 1 0f 2], 2002 -- 2005; UA045.005.027.00004 (Box 27)
    - Overseers [Folder 2 0f 2], 1987 -- 2003; UA045.005.027.00005 (Box 27)
    - Student Orientation, 2002; UA045.005.027.00006 (Box 27)
    - Positioning, 2001 -- 2002; UA045.005.027.00007 (Box 27)
    - Professor of Practice, 1999 -- 2001; UA045.005.027.00008 (Box 27)
    - Research and Scholarship [Folder 1of 2], 1998 -- 2002; UA045.005.027.00009 (Box 27)
    - Research and Scholarship [Folder 2 of 2], 2000 -- 2001; UA045.005.027.00010 (Box 27)
    - Research Policy, 1983 -- 1989; UA045.005.027.00011 (Box 27)
    - Retirement, 1990 -- 2002; UA045.005.027.00012 (Box 27)
    - Special Needs Children Project, 2000 -- 2001; UA045.005.027.00013 (Box 27)
    - Self Study Reports, 1982 -- 1992; UA045.005.027.00014 (Box 27)
    - Sept 11, 2001: Forums on the Tragedy, UA045.005.027.00015 (Box 27)
    - Somerville Advisory Committee, 1988 -- 2003; UA045.005.027.00016 (Box 27)
    - Status Report-1989 Sponsored Programs: College of Liberal Arts, UA045.005.027.00017 (Box 27)
    - Strategic Plan For Research, 1999 -- 2001; UA045.005.027.00018 (Box 27)
    - Student Groups, 2001; UA045.005.027.00019 (Box 27)
    - Student Information, 1996 -- 1998; UA045.005.027.00020 (Box 27)
    - Tech Transfer, 2000 -- 2001; UA045.005.027.00021 (Box 27)
    - Telecom City, 2000 -- 2001; UA045.005.027.00022 (Box 27)
    - (TUFTS) Institute For Leadership, 1998; UA045.005.027.00024 (Box 27)
    - Tufts Longitudianal Health Study/Fitness, 2000 -- 2002; UA045.005.027.00025 (Box 27)
    - Workshops: Funding For Research, 1998 -- 2000; UA045.005.027.00026 (Box 27)
- Correspondence, 1893 -- 2001; UA045.006; 3.9 Linear Feet
  This series consists of correspondence generated in the Office of the Dean of Arts, Sciences, and Engineering by multiple Deans. Multiple Deans of Engineering are represented as different Deans were appointed to various departments within the College of Engineering, such as the Department of Chemical Engineering and the Department of Mechanical Engineering. Reports on various topics may be interfiled.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Dean A and S Chrono. File, 1969 -- 1987; UA045.006.001
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File June, 1987; UA045.006.017.00001 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File May, 1987; UA045.006.017.00002 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File April, 1987; UA045.006.017.00003 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File March, 1987; UA045.006.017.00004 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File February, 1987; UA045.006.017.00005 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File January, 1987; UA045.006.017.00006 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File December, 1986; UA045.006.017.00007 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File November, 1986; UA045.006.017.00008 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File October, 1986; UA045.006.017.00009 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Sept., 1986; UA045.006.017.00010 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File August, 1986; UA045.006.017.00011 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File July, 1986; UA045.006.017.00012 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File June, 1986; UA045.006.017.00013 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File May, 1986; UA045.006.017.00014 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File April, 1986; UA045.006.017.00015 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File March, 1986; UA045.006.017.00016 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File February, 1986; UA045.006.017.00017 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File January, 1986; UA045.006.017.00018 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File December, 1985; UA045.006.017.00019 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Nov., 1985; UA045.006.017.00020 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Oct., 1985; UA045.006.017.00021 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Sept., 1985; UA045.006.017.00022 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Aug., 1985; UA045.006.017.00023 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File July, 1985; UA045.006.017.00024 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File June, 1985; UA045.006.017.00025 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File May, 1985; UA045.006.017.00026 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File April, 1985; UA045.006.017.00027 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File March, 1985; UA045.006.017.00028 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File February, 1985; UA045.006.017.00029 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Jan., 1985; UA045.006.017.00030 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Dec, 1984; UA045.006.017.00031 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Nov., 1984; UA045.006.017.00032 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Oct, 1984; UA045.006.017.00033 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Sept., 1984; UA045.006.017.00034 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Aug., 1984; UA045.006.017.00035 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Jl., 1984; UA045.006.017.00036 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Jn., 1984; UA045.006.017.00037 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File May, 1984; UA045.006.017.00038 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Apr., 1984; UA045.006.017.00039 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File March, 1984; UA045.006.017.00040 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Feb, 1984; UA045.006.017.00041 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Jan., 1984; UA045.006.017.00042 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Dec, 1983; UA045.006.017.00043 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Nov, 1983; UA045.006.017.00044 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Oct, 1983; UA045.006.017.00045 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Sept, 1983; UA045.006.017.00046 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Aug., 1983; UA045.006.017.00047 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File July, 1983; UA045.006.017.00048 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Jn., 1983; UA045.006.017.00049 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File May, 1983; UA045.006.017.00050 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Apr., 1983; UA045.006.017.00051 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Mar., 1983; UA045.006.017.00052 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Feb, 1983; UA045.006.017.00053 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Jan, 1983; UA045.006.017.00054 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Dec, 1982; UA045.006.017.00055 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Nov, 1982; UA045.006.017.00056 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Oct, 1982; UA045.006.017.00057 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Sept, 1982; UA045.006.017.00058 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Aug., 1982; UA045.006.017.00059 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Jl., 1982; UA045.006.017.00060 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Jun., 1982; UA045.006.017.00061 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File May, 1982; UA045.006.017.00062 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Apr., 1982; UA045.006.017.00063 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Mar, 1982; UA045.006.017.00064 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Feb, 1982; UA045.006.017.00065 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File Jan., 1982; UA045.006.017.00066 (Box 17)
    - Dean A and S Chrono. File, 1981; UA045.006.017.00067 (Box 17)
    - Deans A and S Chrono. File Dec., 1980; UA045.006.020.00001 (Box UA045 Shared 1)
    - Deans A and S Chrono. File Nov., 1980; UA045.006.020.00002 (Box UA045 Shared 1)
    - Deans A and S Chrono. File Oct., 1980; UA045.006.020.00003 (Box UA045 Shared 1)
    - Deans A and S Chrono. File Sept., 1980; UA045.006.020.00004 (Box UA045 Shared 1)
    - Deans A and S Chrono. File Aug., 1980; UA045.006.020.00005 (Box UA045 Shared 1)
    - Deans A and S Chrono. File July, 1980; UA045.006.020.00006 (Box UA045 Shared 1)
    - Deans A and S Chrono. File Jan.-June, 1980; UA045.006.020.00007 (Box UA045 Shared 1)
    - Correspondence [Russell Miller File], 1969 -- 1982; UA045.006.020.00008 (Box UA045 Shared 1)
  - Glater and Ernst Correspondence, 1993 -- 2001; UA045.006.002
    Multiple Deans are represented within the Office of the Dean of Arts, Sciences and Engineering. From the Department of Political Science website, accessed 2007-08-08 "Associate Professor Marilyn T. Glater - American Constitutional Law, J.D. Yale Law School, 1967. Prior to coming to Tufts, Professor Glater worked as Director of the Advocacy Department of the King Neighborhood Health Center in New York, as a consultant to Boston's Model Cities Agency and other community organizations, and as a lawyer in private practice. She teaches courses in constitutional law, civil liberties, comparative law and law and society. Glater, a former chair of the Department of Political Science, served as Dean of the Colleges of Liberal Arts and Jackson College for Natural and Social Sciences from 1994-1997." Correspondence by Dean Susan Ernst prior to the split of the Office of the Dean of Arts, Sciences and Engineering is located in UA195/001-001 and -002.
    - Chron. - M.G., 1993 -- 1994; UA045.006.018.00001 (Box 18)
    - Chron - M.G. [1 of 2], 1994 -- 1995; UA045.006.018.00002 (Box 18)
    - Chron - M.G. [2 of 2], 1994 -- 1995; UA045.006.018.00003 (Box 18)
    - MG Chron [1 of 2], 1995 -- 1996; UA045.006.018.00004 (Box 18)
    - MG Chron [2 of 2], 1995 -- 1996; UA045.006.018.00005 (Box 18)
    - MG Chron [1 of 2], 1996 -- 1997; UA045.006.018.00006 (Box 18)
    - MG Chron [2 of 2], 1996 -- 1997; UA045.006.018.00007 (Box 18)
    - Ernst's Chronological, 1997 -- 1998; UA045.006.018.00008 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological, 1998; UA045.006.018.00009 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological, 1998; UA045.006.018.00010 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological [1 of 2], 1999; UA045.006.018.00011 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological [2 of 2], 1999; UA045.006.018.00012 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological, 1999; UA045.006.018.00013 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological, 1999; UA045.006.018.00014 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological, 2000; UA045.006.018.00015 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological Apr. - Sept., 2000; UA045.006.018.00016 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological, 2000; UA045.006.018.00017 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological [1 of 2], 2001; UA045.006.018.00018 (Box 18)
    - Ernst Chronological [2 of 2], 2001; UA045.006.018.00019 (Box 18)
  - Deans of Engineering and internal departments, 1893 -- 1971; UA045.006.003
    Material moved from UA007. Fit with this collection more cohesively. VAM and ALG--4/3/09.
    - Deans and internal, 1946 -- 1957; UA045.006.023.00001 (Box 23)
    - Deans and internal, 1948 -- 1957; UA045.006.023.00002 (Box 23)
    - Gage testing laboratories [folder], 1946; UA045.006.023.00003 (Box 23)
    - Deans and internal, 1944 -- 1956; UA045.006.023.00004 (Box 23)
    - Deans and internal, 1947 -- 1956; UA045.006.023.00005 (Box 23)
    - Deans and internal, 1948 -- 1954; UA045.006.023.00006 (Box 23)
    - Deans and internal, 1949 -- 1954; UA045.006.023.00007 (Box 23)
    - Deans, purchase and sale of lathes, 1893 -- 1925; UA045.006.023.00008 (Box 23)
    - Letter copying book, 1902 -- 1904; UA045.006.023.00009 (Box 23)
    - Letter copying book, 1899 -- 1902; UA045.006.023.00010 (Box 23)
    - Letter copying book, 1904 -- 1908; UA045.006.023.00011 (Box 23)
    - Letter copying book, 1893 -- 1894; UA045.006.023.00012 (Box 23)
    - Guggenheim jet propulsion fellowship [folder], 1948 -- 1949; UA045.006.024.00001 (Box 24)
    - Deans and internal, 1947 -- 1959; UA045.006.024.00002 (Box 24)
    - Personal miscellaneous applications [chemical engineering department 1950-1957, old business 1948 to 1958], 1949 -- 1957; UA045.006.024.00003 (Box 24)
    - Activity report, 1948; UA045.006.024.00004 (Box 24)
    - Deans and internal, 1959 -- 1971; UA045.006.024.00005 (Box 24)
    - October 1968 grads [folder], UA045.006.024.00006 (Box 24)
    - April 68 degree candidates, 1959 -- 1968; UA045.006.024.00007 (Box 24)
    - Internal, 1902 -- 1959; UA045.006.024.00008 (Box 24)
    - General Electric [folder], 1947 -- 1956; UA045.006.024.00009 (Box 24)
    - Internal, 1959; UA045.006.024.00010 (Box 24)
    - Laboratory reactors [folder], 1957; UA045.006.024.00011 (Box 24)
    - General Motors [folder], 1955 -- 1957; UA045.006.024.00012 (Box 24)
    - Industrial science and engineering [folder], 1953 -- 1960; UA045.006.024.00013 (Box 24)
    - Institute of Radio Engineers [folder], 1954; UA045.006.024.00014 (Box 24)
    - Deans and internal, 1949 -- 1954; UA045.006.024.00015 (Box 24)
    - Research Corporation, 1945; UA045.006.024.00016 (Box 24)
    - Lowell report, 1948 -- 1951; UA045.006.024.00017 (Box 24)
- Appointment Books, 1990 -- 1997; UA045.007; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains appointment books from the Office of the Dean of Arts, Sciences and Engineering. Specific Deans within this office are represented by the books. The appointment books of Susan Ernst, whose term within the Office covers both before and after the split of the Office are housed in the UA195, Office of the Dean of Arts and Sciences Collection.
  - [Glater 1990 Appointment Book], UA045.007.019.00001 (Box 19)
  - [Glater 1991 Appointment Book], UA045.007.019.00002 (Box 19)
  - [Glater 1992 Appointment Book], UA045.007.019.00003 (Box 19)
  - [Glater 1993 Appointment Book], UA045.007.019.00004 (Box 19)
  - [Glater 1994 Appointment Book], UA045.007.019.00005 (Box 19)
  - [Glater 1995 Appointment Book], UA045.007.019.00006 (Box 19)
  - [Glater 1996 Appointment Book], UA045.007.019.00007 (Box 19)
  - [Glater 1997 Appointment Book], UA045.007.019.00008 (Box 19)